do I seem like an anti-m mindfulness
person too crotchety to be mindful
because all the mindfulness people are
like so
nice I'm Angela Duckworth and I'm Steven
Dubner I'm a psychologist at Penn and I
run an educational nonprofit called
character lab you also wrote the book
grit yes and I am a writer and I host a
podcast called Freakonomics radio and
you wrote the book Freakonomics among
quite a few others I did and you and I
became friends we did and we discovered
that both of us really like to ask each
other questions and there's only one
rule the rule is there are no stupid
questions today on no stupid questions
how do you keep from losing your temper
over things that just don't matter I
have a terrible temper and when it
erupts it's pretty bad I'm so angry I'm
going to go read poetry also why do so
many of us have greater sympathy for
dogs than humans I superimpose onto the
face of every person who's annoying me
the face of some dog this makes you
nicer to them suddenly I am empathetic
toward every
person Angela Duckworth I have a
question to ask you may I mhm so it
strikes me that many people at least in
the US at least in the year 2020 are
very quick to anger often about
relatively trivial things I may be wrong
and it may also just be that the Avenues
for expressing anger are so available
social media and so on but I've been
reading a little bit of senica lately
the ancient stoic Roman philosopher who
had a lot to say about a lot of things
including anger he wrote about the
detriments of anger and basically how to
keep your cool and he had some advice
shifting your perspective to empathize
with the other person or to spend more
time with less angry people so let me
just ask do you also believe that too
many people get angry over too many
quotidian things and do you find
senica's Dusty advice for how to keep
your cool still valid
and what's your advice for keeping your
cool so I'm not sure that there is more
anger going around these days than in
the past if you look at research on
violence in general those Trends over
the last few hundred years are all
toward being a much more gentle Society
it could also be that we just get angry
over smaller things now that we're not
concerned so much about murder and
Mayhem as in the past we have that
luxury yeah regard of Trends over
centuries I first of all would agree
with you that some of the technologies
that we have available for immediately
expressing and amplifying our anger like
Twitter or you read an op-ed or an
article and you are incensed and write
an all caps comment I mean think about
it in the past you had to get out a
piece of paper and a pen and find a
stamp and an envelope and these are
things that probably made 99% of the
angry comments like yeah but I don't
have enough energy to do that so we
might be getting the immediate
expression of anger in a way that we
didn't before in terms of Dusty old
advice I think some of that Dusty old
advice is fantastic and I'm not an
expert on the stoics or senica in
particular they had a lot of great
advice and the modern incarnation of
this anger management advice is probably
best communicated by a Stanford
psychologist that I know very well named
James gross who was no coincidence well
it's total coincidence I guess he was a
philosophy major so we've actually had
conversations about how the stoics
talked about anger management and I
think by and large it matches up pretty
nicely with some of the modern
theorizing of like how we regulate
emotions including anger what was the
phrase you used emotional what
regulation emotion regulation is the
phrase that psychologist use but you
know you could say it like anger
management emotion regulation the idea
is that you have an emotion and then you
decide whether you want to have that
emotion more or less and then you do
something about it wait a minute you
already lost most of us there exactly
right you probably think you can't
really do anything about your emotions
they come and go and they're not things
that can be controlled is that what you
think well yes and also that there is
necessarily A Time Lapse between
experiencing the emotion and acting on
the emotion I think that's what we see a
lot is that people experience an emotion
and immediately respond to it without
thinking oh what is this emotion what
are the Poss possible outcomes if I
express my response in such and such a
way and so on and is this emotion
desirable do I want more of it do I not
want more of it which by the way is
making you sound a lot like a
mindfulness person Stephen I don't know
if you want that honorific I'm pro-
mindfulness oh you're pro- mindfulness
do I seem like an anti- mindfulness
person sort of too crotchety to be
mindful cuz all the mindfulness people
are like so nice I find a lot of that is
I don't want to say a veneer quite I
used to spend a lot of time in a place
where there was a big Buddhist Monastery
that a lot of people from New York City
would go up to but there were a lot of
what we used to call temporary and angry
Buddhists there people who' come up for
their kind of fix and then walk away
thinking that they had mastered a
certain form of emotion regulation they
would just project a slight veneer of
sang fad whereas in fact they were so
angry just below the surface their blood
was boiling so I actually feel like I'm
a pretty un angry person but when I do
experience a strong response to
something I do tend to not Tamp it down
crotchety is how you defined it it's
okay by the way to feel angry I'm not
saying that you should regulate every
emotion and that when you experience
something like anger you should
immediately Tamp it down anger is an
emotion that is observed across all
cultures and useful yes and useful like
most emotions You could argue all
emotions evolved for survival purposes I
think the consensus is and the
scientific community that anger is the
feeling when you think that your rights
have been violated and you have a goal
that's being blocked and that is why
when somebody cuts you off in traffic or
says something that's Contra your
political beliefs you feel a kind of
indignation that your right has been
grievously violated so it's okay to feel
angry sometimes I think for a lot of us
we feel like we're angry too long or
where you get angry over the stupid
things you know if somebody does cut you
off in traffic or says something on
Twitter that makes you mad it's not
clear to me how expressing that anger is
useful you know I'm a pedestrian not a
driver but I would walk around shaking
my fist and pretending to take photos of
cars who had done illegal things and you
to do you do that I mean when I used to
walk around New York City with my kids
when they were little my best idea I've
never done this do you know those price
sticker guns that you use in a grocery
store to put you know $4.99 on you mean
the labels yeah label gun so it's
basically a bumper sticker gun you could
put it on any part of a car and it would
basically say on it something to the
effect of I am an in big letters I was
thinking I'm a jerk but yeah we'll say I
am a jerk fewer letters too and then in
smaller letters it would say because I
like to run over people with my car and
whenever somebody would actually
drive across an intersection where I was
walking I would just have my bumper
sticker gun in my holster and just put
it on their car and then at some point
they would see it and they think oh wow
somebody really thought I was a jerk
you're going to be like the traffic
vigilante okay so let's say this I have
anger toward them but I haven't done
anything about it and I don't like bang
on their car or anything I have done
that once by the way I have slapped
someone's roof of their car and how'd
you feel afterwards well you know the
thing about anger is that in general
emotion researchers don't think that
catharsis like express it you'll get it
out in general that's not the consensus
in the scientific Community it does not
actually reduce your negative emotions
it often increases them so we probably
shouldn't do things like slam our Palm
on cars and by the way my husband thinks
I'm going to get killed one day one of
these motorists is going to feel like
their rights have been violated cuz
somebody's now banging on their car and
they'll just run you over and then
they're going to pull over and kill me
so I think that the question is what is
the optimal way to be angry senica did
have some good advice I think so one of
his words of wisdom was to try to nip it
in the bud and the idea that you would
not want to deal with anger when you
have fully lost it but when you're just
like a little irritated is good advice
and it's consistent with modern
scientific research on emotion
regulation so that sounds perfectly
sensible I know senica also advised
you should read poetry and history to
amuse yourself and to be diverted was he
selling a book was he like you should
read my poetry I don't know but I will
say this sometimes when I come home at
the end of a day and I've had a
particularly difficult day one of the
first things I do is I just reach
there's a particular volume of poetry
that I happen to like a lot these days
I'd read a few poems and I feel great it
really works for me when's the last time
you were angry tell me about it and then
did you reach for that volume of poetry
well I've been in lockdown with my
family for the past gosh two months or
longer you know living in New York City
and my wife was sick and we were very
very worried and there were periods in
there where one of my kids honestly they
being great and very helpful and so on
but still they're teenagers they're
locked up they both got yanked out of
school and they would do or say
something that I would get really angry
with and I would recognize it wasn't an
offense deserving the level of my anger
and I would just remove myself from the
situation I wouldn't say like I'm so
angry I'm going to go read poetry I
would just leave the room and I would
just then go sit and close the door and
for 10 or 15 minutes read some in this
case Yehuda amihai poetry and it would
make me feel like part of the human
family again in a way that I hadn't 10
minutes ago was very evolved I'm going
to give you an a Stephen for that for a
crouchy person it's curved no I think
it's a really evolved response to anger
because I mentioned this psychologist
James gross and his advice when you're
angry is first and foremost to change
your situation leave the room change the
actual circumstances that are making you
angry the second thing you know when you
drew your attention to something else I
mean that's why a lot of people read I
read before bed every night and it's
specifically to take my mind off of of
everything that is bothering me so you
distracted yourself he calls that
selective attention and then finally you
get some points for just having some
strategy at all because I think the
problem with anger is that even though
senica wants us to nip it in the bud for
me when I lose my temper it is like the
horses leaving the barn and the idea
that you would have some kind of
intentional strategy so that this
doesn't happen too often or too badly
yeah I'll give you an a have you got
better over time you know I actually had
to call James gross for some personal
and professional advice because that is
probably my one greatest ailles heel I
have a terrible temper and when it
erupts it's pretty bad and yeah I have
gotten better at it because I think when
you notice this pattern of losing your
temper I started being really proactive
like for me it's holiday time it's
in-law stuff so I
preventively looked to find ways to
reduce stress around those times of the
year where like well in the last 20
years I've consistently lost my temper
so what can I do differently we've
talked about dealing with your own anger
how to modulate what about dealing with
another person's anger do you have any
advice for the best way to interact with
an angry person well there's an idea
that's not mine it came from some
friends of mine in Psychology Barbara
Millers and Phil tetlock and they had
the idea that instead of doing what we
reflexively would want to do which is
just to argue the opposite position we
gist what the other person said you know
like what's the gist of what you're
saying so they're using it as a verb try
to repeat what the position is of the
person who you think is a flaming idiot
and you do it in a dispassionate
non-judgmental way is the idea that if
you gist them well then they will hear
the gist and say oh God that's idiotic
what was I thinking no it's kind of a
perspective taking or an empathy
exercise so you can really appreciate
the full extent of their argument that
that's one step in any resolution anyway
the second thing is it makes that other
person feel respected and heard one of
the problems when you get into arguments
is that you scream louder but you feel
like you're being heard even less and I
think that this goes in the opposite
direction right like you actually feel
heard and then you deescalate a little
bit your own emotion and your
oppositional stance so the idea was very
simple which is that like if people were
asked to gist each others are like would
it deescalate some of these angry
interactions because you know don't you
feel stepen like nobody's really
listening to anybody else they're just
trying to Ram through their own point of
view I'm sorry I wasn't paying attention
to what you said sorry I was thinking my
own thoughts yes I do I do feel that a
lot and where I see a lot of people
going wrong is that they get very upset
they spend a lot of emotional currency
on things that so don't matter in their
lives it's ether it's smoke it means
absolutely nothing now do you see that
mostly in online exchanges or do you see
that in other ways too I see it in other
ways these days if you're walking down
the street in New York City I'd say
probably 90 to 95% of people are wearing
masks then there's you know a couple
people who are not wearing a mask and
you can see in the body language of the
people who are wearing masks the way
that they Veer from that person and
shoot them dirty looks and I'm not
saying I don't feel those instincts as
well but you don't look contemptuously
at them so what would you do in that
case someone walking down the street
without the mask oh I this is not a
hypothetical I have had on more than one
occasion unfortunately people who I
really feel like hello I was recently at
the grocery store there's an arrow on
the floor and I was going with the arrow
cuz I'm a law-abiding grocery Shopper
and a woman carrying lots of stuff she's
going against the arrow and first I shot
her a dirty look it's harder with a mask
well it is because I asked Paul rosin
the psychologist who studied discussed
you know what is the facial expression
of contempt and he said it's a lopsided
sneer it's an asymmetric snear so I
can't do that with my mask on you have
to work out your eyebrows yeah so I
tried to knit my eyebrows together and
then I realized no I'm going to go with
a verbal expression I was like excuse me
the arrow is pointing the other way she
looked at me she looked at the arrow she
looked at me she looked at the arrow and
then she just kept going against the
arrow which only made me more angry and
that's when you wished you were carrying
a star of death and you would have
nailed her in the back with it well I
have to say yes this feeling that you
want to avenge you want to punish this
other person I will be honest I felt
that let me ask you this having had this
grocery store encounter and having
discussed senica and James gross and
others today what will you do the next
time you're in that situation will you
change your behavior the next time I am
in a grocery store and and somebody's
going against the arrow you know what I
will not flash them a look of contempt I
will move to a different aisle if I put
it in perspective it's a tiny little
part of my reality now let me just ask
you about the costs and benefits of Your
Action so you're moving yourself which
is at some cost probably not very much
in this case unless you were like on a
short line you have to move to a much
longer line etc etc and then the
benefits of you know what you did to her
do you think it actually changed her
behavior maybe long term I mean was it
worth it well that's the interesting
thing I do wonder whether like if you
get shot 100 Dirty Looks by strangers in
the grocery store in the street maybe
you'll reform but doesn't feel like that
does it when you shake your fist at a
motorist for running the red light you
don't really feel like that person's
like oh I'm going to stop doing that my
Reckoning is the kind of person who
would do a behavior that would get me
that upset is not the kind of person
who's going to take my fish shaking as a
serious reprimand I think that's right
let me ask you finally do you feel any
less potentially angry in general having
had this conversation about anger well
I'm going to certainly feel angry again
in the next 24 hours even in some small
form and I feel pretty good about like
having a little senica in the back
pocket to think what would senica do you
know I feel this has helpful to me
because the next time I have a situation
like that I'm going to say Well Angie
was in the grocery store the lady going
against the arrow and she got really
pissed and I'm not going to do that
anything I do shy of that is going to be
a victory so for me I'll say what would
senica do and you could say what would
Angela not
do still to come on no stupid questions
you're handling all the dog poop for
your neighborhood and you're the people
who don't have a dog no wonder you hate
[Music]
dogs Stephen you have a dog I do and I
do not have a dog you don't you're a cat
person apparently I don't have a cat
either I am in the like one out of three
American households that doesn't have
any pet but here's my curiosity about
dogs and dog owners I get that this
provides some kind of comfort to you but
I guess I'm wondering how far does this
go is there anything that you wouldn't
do for this Kine that you love so much
so I do love the dog the dog is named
Fifi that's completely ridiculous if
you're of a certain age it's a
ridiculous name because Fifi is like the
stereotypical name of the French poodle
in Looney Tunes or something yeah what
happened is when we got our puppy our
daughter Ana who's kind of a Francophile
she really wanted a French name and all
the French names we could think of were
beautiful female names that didn't sound
at all like dog names like Adele or
claudet or something yeah just not dog
names at all and so I said kind of
jokingly Fifi which is like you know the
equivalent of Rover or phto but Ana my
kid she'd never heard of Fifi so she
thought oh my God it's so beautiful and
elegant and French so we went with it
now you have a dog named Fifi yep and
she looks like a fifi she's a small
white dog very adorable love her very
much but the question is what would I
not do how far would you go for Fifi
okay so if what you're trying to get at
here is do I treat her better than I
treat people which I kind of gather is
your subtext people do seem to treat
their pets dogs especially better than
they treat other humans in some cases I
totally agree and I do think it's kind
of tragic honestly and yet I participate
and yet I'm empathetic toward almost
every dog and I think wait a minute why
would I be empathetic to a strange dog
and think ill of some strange person
isn't the person you know higher order
capable of more more deserving of
empathy more worthy and yet I feel that
my Association is probably not so
uncommon and I'm glad you asked me about
it cuz I think about it a lot and it
bothers me I'm so guilty of being dog
Centric or
proog that when I'm in a foul mood and
let's say I'm walking down the street
and it's a crowded sidewalk you know
there's just a lot of people and they're
kind of weaving in and out or getting in
the way and I feel myself getting
annoyed and I think what am I doing
these people are doing nothing wrong
they're just walking down the street why
am I getting annoyed at them and I
realize it's just cuz I'm a little
impatient or cranky whatever so what I
do I have this trick which is I
superimpose onto the face of every
person who's annoying me the face of
some
dog this makes you nicer to them it does
okay it does sound pretty ridiculous now
that I say
I put dog faces on all the people and
then I find suddenly I'm empathetic
toward every I find the whole thing
puzzling honestly if I were like
pitching a venture capist in a
hypothetical role that didn't have pets
and I'm like okay we're going to have
these animals they're going to be
domesticated they're going to sh they're
going to pee they're going to of course
die before you do so you're going to be
really unhappy even desperately
depressed after your pet nobody would
invest in that idea it's so ridiculous
also there is is a problem in my
neighborhood where the dog owners will
tie up their tidy little bag of dog poo
but then just leave it and my husband
installed this industrialized trash can
right outside our house and then we
personally are basically curbing the
dogs for the entire neighborhood you're
handling all the dog poop for your
neighborhood and you're the people who
don't have a dog no wonder you hate dogs
I know I got a little chip on my
shoulder with that we want did a fre
economics radio episode about this theme
it was called which came first the
chicken or the avocado and it was about
the moral outrage that people feel about
the mistreatment of animals when they
often don't feel outrage over the
mistreatment of humans and I'll start
with the animal in the story it wasn't
actually a chicken it was a giraffe do
you remember there was a giraffe named
Marius who lived in a zoo in Copenhagen
and he was dissected in front of a bunch
bunch of children who were visiting the
zoo oh no now he was dead and they were
cutting him up to show an autopsy or
dissection it's like a biology study or
something yeah yeah something like that
and it became a huge Global outcry and a
kind of outpouring of sympathy for poor
Marius the giraffe and at the same time
I'd become aware that the avocados that
most Americans eat are primarily
imported from Mex Meo in places where
criminals extort and kill and do other
things to the farmers who grow them in
other words our avocados are kind of you
know blood avocados it's like blood on
our hands yeah but nobody seems to care
when they're having guacamole that oh
the actual people who work to grow these
things are being beat up and ransomed
and things like this whereas poor Marius
there was so much empathy and to go
beyond the avocados what about you know
a million Syrian refugees yeah there's a
lot of hand ringing and teeth nashing
but Marius the giraffe seemed to gather
more sympathy and that depresses me but
it also doesn't surprise me okay so
there's a lot of things going on with
Marius the giraffe right like first of
all what a adorable name I mean maybe
the name was part of and then also one
giraffe is probably somehow more
compelling than like plurality good
point you know all the research showing
that we're more sympathetic to a story
of one particular individual I guess
this case an individual giraffe but let
me make a comparison which I think is
even more direct so you've got this dog
Fifi that costs you some amount of money
why don't we donate the equivalent
amount of money that we spend for
Extraordinary and even ordinary expenses
that have to do with caring for our pets
like thousands of dollars why don't we
donate that amount of money to very
worthy human causes education hunger
there was a study by these so I ologists
at Northeastern who were looking into
the question of whether people human
subjects are more emotionally disturbed
by abuse of animals versus people and
they found let me see here I'll read a
bit we found more empathy for victims
who are human children so children
puppies and full- grown dogs than for
victims who are adult humans okay so it
doesn't even have to be a puppy full-
grown dogs the full grown dogs come in
before the full grown humans right I do
find it troubling but I think the
simplest explanation is that it's easier
to feel empathy or to exhibit kindness
toward pets even strange pets than to
strange people or sometimes even people
we know well and I think the answer lies
in your field somehow in Psychology in
that we tabulate the wrongdoing of other
humans you know moral failings or
behaviors we disapprove of in some way
so we have mixed feelings maybe about
our fellow human mixed at best but the
dogs are like n they're pretty good I
think it's the Paradox of the dog they
aren't capable of that much so we can't
blame them for that much you know what's
the worst thing a dog can do can chew up
your couch or maybe poop on your floor
and those are pretty forgivable but the
person you know can do something a lot
worse than that right they certainly
haven't schemed in a really
sophisticated evil way but it does
disturb me how Baseline empathetic I am
toward any dog on the street versus any
person on the street and I would like to
change so can you help me other than
just thinking of people as dogs um which
seems to help you well to be a little
nitpicky I don't think you really mean
empathy right you don't mean it in the
kind of narrow sense that like I'm
feeling what you're feeling because
that's one of the classic philosophical
questions can you really feel what like
a dog might feel or like a goldfinch or
something because you really will never
know what it feels like to be a dog
right well maybe sympathy rather than
empathy what do you mean when you say
that I guess the word I would use is
sympathy in that if I see a dog out in
the rain I'm like oh poor dog if I see a
person out in the rain I think what are
the circumstances that led to that
person being there did they make bad
choices ah this is revealing you feel
like a dog is innocent and a little bit
like they have certain limitations that
would make you feel more moved I guess
when you see them suffering and maybe
more responsible to help them right and
they have less agency and fewer
opportunities to do things that might
upset other humans I mean here's the
thing that might be an explanation for
this but I think it's controversial
which is that dogs are one of the things
that make people happy like happier than
almost anything that would be an
explanation for why you would want to
privilege them in a moral dilemma or why
walking down a crowded sidewalk in New
York helps to think about other people
as dogs because they're such a source of
Happiness if Fifi were not in your life
if you could just imagine that
counterfactual do you think you would be
a little less happy than you are today
yeah I probably would I mean I grew up
with dogs but then I lived for many many
many years without a dog and was totally
fine so I like Fifi if she disappeared
tomorrow I would miss her I would mourn
her but no I'd be fine it's not like
with a person yes okay well that's good
that was the right answer pH you pass
but Steven Dubner plus Fifi is happier
than Steven dubar without any kind of
Fifi yes every pet owner will say of
course yes but the research on whether
pet ownership improves human satisf
action and happiness is mixed just
disputed evidence and I will say this
like I am the primary caregiver of this
dog and it's quite a bit sometimes so
she works I was going to say she works
with me she's doing some filing right
now but she comes to my office with me
every day which is about a 15 20 minute
walk and we're alone all day so I
literally spend more time with FiFi than
I do with any human sometimes it's a
pain in the neck and so on the occasions
when I travel and I leave the dog behind
it's kind of nice to have a breather
from the dog well I would say this yeah
the data are mixed in part because you
can't really easily randomly assign
people to have dogs and not have dogs
and you can't just like kidnap take away
their dogs thank goodness I do find it
really interesting even though the data
aren't there my hypothesis is that for
some people this living creature that is
just always happy to see you and is a
little simpler than human beings and is
more predictably affectionate and I'm
not the first to say this but you know
the need to be needed I mean take
pigeons in the park there are you know a
fair number of human beings who seem to
really enjoy feeding the pigeons even
against the better judgment of some of
their fellow humans who say like stop
doing that they're crapping all over the
place but when you see somebody feeding
the pigeons and you ask yourself why do
they do that I think it's at least
partly because we need to be needed and
a pigeon is in need of your breadcrumbs
and so Fifi is in need of you she
depends on you and I think human beings
like matter in that way I agree as I'm
sure you know there's a lot of evidence
that service to others whether it's
charitable contributions or taking care
of things for people etc etc makes you
feel a lot better makes you feel needed
makes you feel worthy reliably and I
will say this that really works for me
and the dog I feel that little shot of
whatever it is that I get when you feel
temporarily good about yourself when I
just do whatever feed her walk her and
so yeah I think there is is an
interesting reciprocity which is not a
coincidence the reason that they are the
primary domesticated pet is because they
give us that and we give them that but
if we're looking for long-term wisdom or
guidance on the value of human versus
animal one of my favorite passages from
the talmud deals with this kind of
directly there was a famous line in
Ecclesiastes said that a living dog is
better than a dead lion which is about
like status and rank but then in the
talad the talud is telling the story
about when King David dies and his son
Solomon referring to that line says
something like is it not true that alive
dog is better than a dead lion and this
was referring to Solomon's question of
what should be done about his father
King David had died and was out in the
sun and the dogs were coming around
wanting to eat him so he had to ask what
should be done what takes precedence
here and it was interesting because most
Jews throughout history did not have
dogs it was just not a very Jewish thing
to have I didn't know that and yet for
me as a dog owner and someone who's
Jewish I find it very nice to know that
even as far back as atama there was this
notion that a dog as a living thing had
more value on some Dimensions than a
person who happened to be dead who was
even a king well I think all
rationalization to make the habit of
having a dog seem like the right thing
to do is completely uh legitimate go for
it even if you have to go back 2,000
years to a religious text
right no stupid questions is part of the
Freakonomics radio network this episode
was produced by me Rebecca Lee Douglas
and I'm here with a fact check of
today's conversation during the first
half of the episode Angela shares her
frustration with a particular Shopper
who was not following pandemic rules at
her local grocery store Steven
empathizes with Angela's desire for
vengeance and suggests that Angela
probably wish she were carrying a quote
star of death what Steven likely meant
was a throwing star shuken in Japanese
you might have heard of them as ninja
stars but it's unclear whether ninjas
actually used them original ninjas were
very low Tech and didn't fight with
nunchucks or many of the other gadgets
that they're seen using in movies and
pop culture and contrary to Steven's
suggestion no stupid questions
officially recommends that you leave
your throwing stars at home and do not
bring them with you to purchase
groceries later on in the episode Steven
mentions the controversy over Marius the
giraffe it's true that Marius was
publicly dissected before a crowd at the
Copenhagen Zoo but the Uproar actually
began much earlier protesters had
rallied after the zoo announced plans to
euthanize the 18-month-old giraffe
because his genes were considered too
common for breeding anger grew when the
public found out that Marius had been
shot and after the dissection fed to
some of the zoo's nious animals finally
Steven wax is poetic about his dog Fifi
which is indeed a go-to name for a
French poodle Angela thought that there
might be a cartoon character that fits
that description and in fact there are
many Fifi was Minnie Mouse's pet and
Pluto's love interest for years she was
depicted as a Pines which is not a
French poodle but is also very fluffy in
the 1980s movie life is a circus Charlie
Brown we get a more stereotypical Fifi
when Snoopy falls in love with a white
poodle at the circus this Fifi returned
in the 2015 Peanuts movie and was voiced
by Christen chenowith granted she
doesn't really speak but chenowith did
lend her Broadway vocals to make some
cute squeaky doglike sounds that's it
for the fact
check no stupid questions is produced by
Freakonomics radio and Stitcher our
staff includes Allison craigo Greg
rippen James Foster and Karen Wallace
our theme song is and she was by Talking
Heads special thanks to David burn and
Warner Chapel Music if you'd like to
listen to our show ad free subscribe to
Stitcher premium and to read about or
hear more no stupid questions visit
freecomic
nsq you can also follow us on Instagram
and Twitter at nsq show and on Facebook
at nsq show thanks for
listening if Fifi were kidnapped in some
foreign country and they said you have
to sell your children to get her back I
yeah I would definitely give up at least
one of my teenagers okay good that would
be
win-win Stitcher